Okay, we're going to call it the Army City Council for this regular day and time.
Two of the public input on schedule personal appearances is the Army Council on the agenda items.
I think three of us could send in generous.
Staff is recommending a forward vibe which again are claims of minutes.
There are no questions that entertain a motion to approve this recommended.
Motion approved.
And the second.
Second.
Low call.
Question.
Who is working?
Forceder.
Solves.
Item five is contract for the city of Miami,
Anyhow.
And there is smithy amount of 10,000 for the, which,
10,000 is the city's portion for work in the 66 cultural district.
Prove the claim and approve the budget amendment number 20-04B General Fund City
and I believe you guys talked to MDRA yesterday a little bit about this also.
I think we brought them into the loop.
Okay.
You want to give us an overview.
But you're an overview and I'll also answer a few questions that have been asked previously and been
if you have more questions.
Okay.
So, Dean passed me with a new department to the Department of Library Arts and Culture.
And one of the things that I'm supposed to do is to help increase activity
downtown.
And that's that's part of what we're looking to do.
It is a cooperative project with Anyhow, but also with a MIMA Arts and Humanities Council.
I took a little bit about that in the email that I sent out.
I only had one person respond with a question which let me know that I've related and
explaining very well how that would work.
The city will be contributing $10,000 like a check to Anyhow.
However, of those funds, $7,400 if a pretty wide view would be city funds.
The remaining 2,600 would come from the LIMA Arts and Humanities Council.
We are 66 cultural district grant that we receive a peer that we've received for the past four years.
And the reason for that is this grant is specifically designed to help market the cultural district.
We use it for several different things.
But this fits in perfectly with the purpose of the grant.
And so for this year's grant, we would use the funds for that.
And so the Arts Council would make the check out to the city.
And then the city would make the $10,000 check out.
So the Arts Council brought us a check for $24,300.
$26,300.
Yes.
So that's how that's how we would do that.
Another question I was asked and I tried to answer that within the email.
I'll mention it again, is where do we come up with the Arts Math?
Well, Aaron has worked...
worked for NEO for the past two years.
This is his third year doing NEO theater experience.
Dr. Hale was very pleased with his work.
Dr. Racers, pleased with his work.
I mean, obviously they're having him continue this.
And we did, we did talk with Dr. Racer about this.
He's got a reputation for being very creative.
He's a very hard worker, very energetic.
And he's good at bringing volunteers together.
And I've seen this, even in the mural festival,
me had an activity downtown.
And he had a whole lot of volunteers with him.
I know Ryan has seen this as well in NEO.
And so that kind of draw attention, plus the way
that we're partnering with NEO,
may be the ones that will pay him, give him the monthly payment.
He'll kind of be our hands at that point,
just in terms of making out the checks and that sort of thing.
And two, one of the goals is to bring more NEO students
downtown.
That's something that Ryan and I talked about in the past
is just seeing more of NEO kids downtown.
In addition to that, there are several cultural district
objectives that are included in the contract.
Or I think you go list of some of the things
that he would be doing as well.
And one of the things that I don't think I had explained very well
that came out when we talked with NEO yesterday
was how this would be structured.
He would be working under me.
It's not a contract, but we say, OK, we want you
to market the cultural district, let us know when you're done.
Because this is specific things.
He would be responsible in June.
There would be my oversight, Ryan,
is overseeing the work at NEO as well.
So that's how that would be structured.
And we also would be tracking a lot of things in terms of attendees
and where people were coming from, and that sort of thing.
So those were the main questions that we were asked,
and I would book you to ask more questions now.
So is this a one-year contract more or should we do?
Yes.
And that's a good point to it.
This is a pilot project.
In fact, the contract states that it doesn't imply
that there will be any more contracts or a bottom-of-the-art
amount of free-gay.
Well, this is a one-shot video.
I think the question was answered.
I mean, if we got six months in, you were just really
disappointed with the way things were going.
What a report is the city council, if any.
We would stop.
I mean, it would be.
And I think this is something that we talked about
with Dr. Razer, and I'm not sure about the exactly how
the...
I said that he's working for the college, but he's underneath you.
If two months ended then.
Okay, so he's working for both is the city going to do one lump sum to them and then they figure out or do we pay an out of monthly
stipend of this or how does
So two months in we're not satisfied or three months and we're not satisfied
You know, it's going to reimburse the city back. Does that how that's going to be done exactly?
Because I was one of raise a lot of questions and I'll be the first one to say that
If you want to say no rise guy and I'm going to be start talking about marketing before you ever came on
We always kind of had an internal marketing whether it was what we needed or didn't need I didn't know
Apparently his ability to market sounded like a better thing for the call for this
And and I'm okay with that, but A I just kind of wanted to know why him and not somebody else or did this city if we're giving a donation
Do we have the ability to reach out for somebody that does marketing at this level or does that are only option?
So that was where I came in and just didn't
Didn't get all the answers that I needed for that so my one of the things that I said was is with the money that we're going to give
Are we willing to get you know if we don't get what we want or what you feel is right at any point you can stop
Okay, one of the other things that you you email back you talked about the four of the things
He's going to do four small downtown things. Is this four small downtown things that are new that we're done already?
It's not anything that we well for I say is four new small things and then one new major events
That was one that was really kind of I didn't know if we were piggybacking off of stuff that we've already done
The movie on mainstream that's the one really well. We don't see it. We're going to end up with a strike
But that's that's something. Oh, I mean, it's it's me, but if that's not something that he could come in and do and and he would I mean
We want these things to be something we have at them
Yeah, and I do think to one of your questions
Brian
I know I are not real well
I but I do know him and I would say in our community he's one of the few people that probably have the skills that that's I mean
That maybe somebody in job or some work could be like being part of the college is I think key to what we're trying to accomplish
So that you know somebody else outside if you're not going to hand that
Connection and and and to be the ambition of the marketing
They're also the advance. He's not just marketing those events. He's put it in together and creating them and so that's like almost a different thing
You know if it goes together people market those events
He's the one that's going to you know, well with with me be there
At least one of them is going to be any else to some kind of a downtown of that brain
Well, and like I mentioned in my email, I support this. I just didn't feel like I had all I felt like I was given something and what I was told is is that I have a rough draft contract and I really want a rough draft
I'm trying to know what we were getting for the money and what's our out if we don't if I come along and we donate 70 or $100 to somebody that doesn't have a pan-out
What can we get back in exchange? So that was where I had some concerns all the way up until right now. So I appreciate explaining that
I just had a question this position was not posted anywhere for people to apply for
No, and because it's not he's not employed by the city, this is just a contract and do this specific
So he's not like a city employee, it states that in the contract as well that he's not
Is this dean and so really is this just a donation to the college?
No, I don't think it's a donation to the college is facilitating it, but I wouldn't consider it a donation
It's kind of like we give the chamber 10,000 to the fireworks
And then I see this kind of that same way except for this is something at least on the outside and it's something he's already doing at the college
He's a contract employee at the college and he's not on the payroll in the regular sense, he's a contract employee
And I think the way I see this is we're just pitching in somebody to supplement what he's trying to do to benefit down here
That's really the focus of this is the
And so the arts council's pitching in I don't know what is the college doing 10,000 so the college is pitching in 10
50% of it the arts council's doing about 15% we're going to rest
Do we have any timelines and plenty of when things are going to start happening that we can
That that's something that we will be working out
Yes, there will be timelines and there will be tracking
We have calendar revenge to go on
The contract it would start when
September 15
Okay, we're already just kind of behind
So if I pray tonight, it will start maybe morning
I guess that's the best way
How many hours you think you'll be dedicated to these particular programs?
Excessive, yes
What was an excessive amount of time?
He's almost 18
What's just understand when somebody on the outside
comes up and asks, you know, why is the city who is this person and why? I don't know if that's
what I'm saying. Oh yes. Whether Ryan knows him and thinks he's a great guy. I know him.
He might still be, but I'll believe Ryan. And I go with that. So I have to ask these questions.
I understand. And that's why I did. Yes. So I understand all that. And I've got to ask you
great question. How many hours? Whether he's an OCD guy or not, you want to make sure you're, you know,
is he? But with four small events and one big event and what he's trying to do, I'm going to
guess that he's, he's something that I'm learning. We, we, we, we've got more people. But
here's what I would like this passes. I would like some kind of report back, you know, when
that's orderly or, you know, yes, you know, something new comes about. Yes, that will be great to hear
all and and be all right. We will be given right now. More than likely we'll sit at downtown or
hear about it. Yes. So she read it. Yes. The same kind of needs to. I have no further questions.
Okay. So we have a motion to approve the contract when it's sitting in the mail, but they're in
areas, math and the amount of 10,000. Based on the information that she gave me to not. I will make
that motion. Okay. We have a second. Second. Roll ball. Who's for a stir? All right. For a
question. All right. So that is a bucket truck or a service truck. You can see it. Yes. I
would like to point out that all tech was the second. But the first bit or did not include
everything that we asked for. They did not have an extended cab. They did not have the requirements of the
bit. So we went with all tech. And the first bit I talked to the new day they understood it. They said,
look, we were just trying to get you directly. We had them a lot, you know, more of them. So it's an
understanding. They said, we'll, you know, next time we'll bid it as you know, you said, okay. So this
truck was included in the right study. This was. Yes, sir. It was, it was, it was, it was budget. I mean,
the right study that purchased that right. So and we would take our older, our oldest bucket truck that's
and we'll give it to the parks department so they can use it and for different things like that they need.
So it'll go to get you. Do you hear that? Yes. Yes. Let's get a vehicle number off of that.
Thank you. Thank you 14. Yeah, 14. For the record, 14. Oh, there's broken back. So. Do we have most of your
approval item set? I'll make a motion. And on second, then roll up all the leaves. For us, sir.
All right, shall we? Let's go.
I have questions, but I'm working.
I don't think it's good business, any business, anyone?
Staff report, I don't know, I don't know.
Staff report, so I'm going to do a packet from the staff here
if you have questions.
I think it's mayor and council committee announcements.
Ben or tower, do you know of anything specifically
that we need to have on?
Do we need to have a work session next week?
There's a long short.
I think it was planning on us.
Yes.
That's what I was informed today.
I have one question.
I don't know if you've already passed that, but I was just going to ask about the splash.
We were going to then see if there's a communication committee.
We can go ahead.
No, no, no, no.
Let's be happy.
We're going to go ahead.
I don't let them.
I ask everything to give us that.
I don't know.
11 City Manager Communications, splash pads.
Plac, plant up.
As you know, in late August, the engineers came down and did inspection
on the splash pad and we had 14 panels fail.
Inspection, due to puddling, holding water.
After working with them, they cut nine of them out and replaced them
in September 3rd.
So all the concrete at this point has passed.
This was different from the different color.
This was in puddling, relax.
Yes.
When they replaced that concrete on September 3rd,
that started our 28 day wait time for tough coat all over.
Because part of the runway was in some of the sections that had to be replaced.
So they have to have 28 days of cure time.
So early October, tough coat will be in to the emblem.
And the runway, we had to send some of the features back to powder coat
just because they set in our lock for so long after plastic.
Or some of them in.
Or some of the features are in.
They wore all installed.
But if we pulled some of them back out because the balloon had faded
the sunlight and the rain and the plastic had faded some of the balloon
features.
So they pulled them out and sent them back to powder coat.
Some of the signage was spelled wrong to comb the eight or several
wrongs they sent it back.
It's like a nightmare project.
Well, it's been fun.
I think water for each of your totals.
Do you remember?
I don't know.
Okay.
The fence will be in at the end of next week.
The top coat likes that'll be in and they end of October.
The O-U-2 has finished all of their remediation.
That's the new saw in the hydroceaning.
The front section, the north side of the restroom,
is the steady portion of the saw and it will be in this week.
So that all.
that will be finished up. And the only thing the city will lack is the parking lot. And
as soon as we can get all the features installed and then we'll come in and do the parking
lot. But with that it has cost us a lot of extra time but it has not changed our overall
G&P. So no additional funding has come forward, no additional change orders have come forward.
We've just lost a lot of time and the entire season this season.
If the things are going to fade laying on a parking lot, how are they going to hold that?
When they reached back out to the manufacturer, they said that's very, very unusual because one city
is the unwrapped and they're held up. They don't set covered in plastic for three months with the
amount of rain that we've had in sunshine. And they just set in our law forever just and just got
beat by the sunlight wrapped in plastic. And you can see the actual bubble wrap emblems on the
blue. It just faded it just a little shade lighter and the engineers rejected them and said them all back.
So it's not that they won't fade it all just because of the way they were wrapped and it faded unevenly.
Not even like yeah. Eventually they'll all fade. If you go down to the swimming pool you can see those
those structures that they at least are all beautiful and that they all fade.
It just kind of worried me that we can three months and they've already faded that much.
But we are very, very close. It seems like everything is coming together.
It will be done correctly when it's done. The brownfield side of things, the eagle picture,
side of things. They have side to contract with their contractor to come in the rays and
lower the wellheads to make those all ground level. So it should be a really nice piece of
property when it's all sent down. So when is our warmest armament? We have not had, we do not have
a substantial completion yet. So that will not start till we get that. And the engineers will not accept
that until everything is in place and functioning. So it will get, I mean there's a 12 month
morning we'll get it early here we'll once we get to substantial. Which will probably be after the
tough code we'll be at off top. So we'll go through training, we'll get it fully up and running and then we'll
shut it down. The last week is a good 80, 3 days. Right back up, you can have one week in.
If we go to have one week in, then it's all up for it. Anything else?
Yes, sir. So I'm happy to say that we close in on our sanitary suitors,
stormwater, lo and that we've been where we took before you, for approval, through four months again.
We locked that in a little over at 1.7479% so we're very excited about that for 20 years. So we're excited
about that.
We have, on Main Street we're still waiting on approval from the federal government to, um, to, um, to, okay,
are, uh, our grand portion of that project. Someone figured that project, going, then we'll put that
Main Street out for a bit and continue on on Main Street. So, so, ship all approved it. Yes, sir.
We're waiting on the, yeah. We're waiting on the, so we, we've approved on our, in this data
approved it, so the state has to get federal highway administration is approval since that's where the
grant's coming from. So, we're waiting on that, and then, um, central, if you want to talk about central
on, and over, and over. So, might we get so far into the winter that we end up holding
off on Main Street until next year? Probably not. Yeah. Because the first piece is going to be utilities,
um, we won't let them get the middle of a dinner, something where it sits, broke out all year,
water lines done. So, the strong sewer piece, they could do this winter. Yeah.
They could do the exciting ones. I mean, they could find all we could, or one other, the exciting ones.
We have a winter like last year. They can't. The, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the, the next year.
Because the plant's probably closed, but yeah, we're waiting on federal highway now,
which is shocked to all of us. We didn't know we had another step and we got through the ship. That's what I thought.
Yeah. The things that I want to ship out was down. We would like to point out it is a half a
main dollar. So, it's, I don't know. It is way, I mean, it's far free money, I've never fast. So,
central, central, the water line portion is nearly complete. They pulled their back to samples.
They're waiting on the results of those. They'll get the tie-ins done, and water line will be hot.
They got back on to the source of peace while they're waiting.
We're working through a change where right now, for time, because they have almost five weeks of rain days.
So, they started a project. So, they're looking, you know, membered in now, person's situation.
These have started sidewalk. We've got to get there to do anything's done, and out of there. So, we can get the rest of the painting done.
You know, in overlay project, they're probably 50% through on the sidewalk piece of it.
The painting is essentially done, other than the repairs, and I've talked to him for a staff today.
They're going to try and come back in the next three or four weeks and go ahead and get those patched.
The goal was to have staff come back when they paved, central, and just let them fix everything so that they're
both in all of the lines. But there's substantial completion for that project, was yesterday.
They're going to come in, and they're asking for an extension as well. I didn't remember to get the sidewalk piece done.
We're still working on it. We're going to improve that in a lot. So, you'll probably see a change order at the next council.
questions for Sean or Tyler? Anything else on your list, Tyler?
No, sir, that'd be it.
I am seven. I'm two to one.
We're hiring a good gentleman.
I'm a good gentleman.
Of course I am.
Seven.
Second.
Oh, call.
We're getting you.
Question.
Who is I?
Forster.
All right.